all right hello youtube welcome to fix
our world Friday there are four of us
this week may be an ongoing four of us
I'll see how that that happens how that
plays out
welcome atrial so your first fix our
world Friday I'll bet you've been on the
project reason for a while I added some
things to the agenda I don't know if
anyone else did
I also don't know if I sent up the
agenda in a little other link I just do
that there we go
she got it from Facebook you want to
look at the agenda and add things to it
oh I'd like I'm watching myself talk
about three seconds behind that's weird
there we go I think it's fine now all
right
so my brother and I had a conversation
on the weekend or I think he got the
vision for the meta project what the
game be like having a space for game be
people to come to bring their projects
and figure out what meta project we need
to facilitate that without people ever
having to give up ownership and I think
project raising is a big piece of that
it's what we're already doing we have
our fix for our world Friday which like
our live board meeting put together tech
and creating the meta stuff but we don't
actually like the schedulers where we're
trying because that's is the thing
that's simple enough with enough power
that can have a drastic impact in the
game be space and in in a world so what
I have on the schedule is what we were
talking about on the weekend which is
what do we need in place to start
another YouTube channel that's actually
together tech that does that piece of it
right has our live board meetings has
our project brazing has hopefully even
like mastermind groups which might be
what this one is or like this is either
a mastermind group we're bringing our
projects and moving forward with them or
the mentor project one I also kind of oh
I don't know how to the agenda
a fourth which might be more of the idea
Cafe which is like a missing imaginary
conversation like a conversation of
imagining a better world why is the leg
so that I'm gonna turn off my camera and
move to another location so I'm closer
to my Wi-Fi if somebody else wants to
talk for a moment okay I like all of
that where you go and ghibli one quick
thing to mention about the scheduling
tool is that someone did mention an area
where they have something similar that I
didn't think of is gambling websites
where you're playing like cards against
people so I don't know that they've the
full scheduling thing but they do have a
thing to where you can kind of say when
you're available and it groups people
into small groups so I don't know how
I'm gonna check to see if there's any
help in source versions of that already
out that we can build on top of rather
than building from scratch probably not
but it was just an interesting and also
maybe to look at for features and ideas
because they've been doing for a long
long time but I thought that was an
interesting little Court Mike says could
be actually a solution the the vices
have largely built the Internet as we
know it so yes sure
so much is known figure out how to
incorporate pornography and it will be
set yeah I'm ready gamifying it so
really that that's the big three yeah
[Music]
though you mentioned they also like a
YouTube channel are we are we
comfortable with the name I'm fine with
together tech but we also discussed
several other things I just want to see
where everyone's at hon if we discuss
other thanks what were the other names
that were together tech it's like a name
that explains it and it's a placeholder
yeah I guess the only thing is so is it
is it definitely gonna be tech you know
we talked about solutions right I think
that the only thing I was thinking I
think it will be
I think there's gonna end up being like
I don't know if you want to call it like
child companies or what that wouldn't be
necessarily tech but I think like the
main thing that the the framework that
dragged all the pieces and touches
everything I think that will end up
being tech I think art yeah like our
tagline is something with solutions in
it like iterative solute iterative
solutions we create together it isn't
that but something along those lines
okay that explains it more but together
Tech is both like we're creating tech
together and everyone can do it and
everyone can come be part of it
like if I'm here to Creighton Tech and
you want to come for a tech know I've
with another name but the YouTube
channel together Tech doesn't exist yet
so we might as well yeah it's it's a
little hard to change a name I think on
YouTube once you create a channel for it
but it that should be fine I think we're
good
I cannot help in creating that channel
because YouTube put a restriction on me
because I created too many channels I
can only do one here I think I've
already created it within three interns
okay I think when I last cuz I just did
the wiki election one like a couple
weeks ago I think it said I could do
three a year for my phone number so I
can still technically do it yeah so I
don't want to be the one to do it part
of the reason I don't want to be the one
to do it is I'm at the limit with crowd
democracy for my stream yard of 20 hours
a month and that's one of the reasons I
would like to have a new youtube one and
if I was the one creating it and doing
that then I would I wouldn't know how to
sign out and sign in and do that and I
feel like you guys should all have that
more the ability to do that much more
easily than I do but I do think it needs
to be like a corporate account like it
needs to be a productive remember anyone
can sign in and anyone could so if no
one else is available but I could sign
in and sign out and I'll figure that out
but then it's like one name we have the
password yeah we'll have to figure out
how it works with like multiple Pete
like is it a shared account or can you
assign different users to the same
account where it's our accounts and then
we can all go and do it well we'll have
to figure that out for both YouTube
for first community and then what
exactly I mean I think much like this
channel has been it isn't let's figure
out the final product and out and put it
out let's like keep project raising and
that might have all been to something
else let's keep you know fix our world
Friday and that might involve into
something else and having mastermind
groups but before we start it having
some idea of what the different shows
are right and who is the general / the
brand like what what why are we doing it
what is it going towards do we even need
to or is it just you know one step above
where we are now maybe we don't need to
yeah I mean I think we do but just to
actually talk through it and sort of get
Joe if you don't mind starting that I
can definitely help you out I've create
enough channels and I'm pretty sure if
you make just another channel you can
add or remove channel managers so I
would imagine so yeah I haven't done
that but or not easy but like something
that but if you bump in anything feel
free to reach out to me
and if you are running out of limits or
sudden I can be a backup perfect the
logo and stuff for that for together
tech no no I just want to know where at
on that note Jubilee
I know together tech org is up what what
do we want to do on start keeping that
updated yeah because I thought it can't
be me there was someone who kind of I
was gonna take that on named Matt and
then he fell off I'm sure he fell off
the face that were or just doesn't exist
anymore
so I can't like I can write blogs but I
can't get my thinker to start with
until we get somebody involved at once
to the website can just sort of be a
placeholder pointing to the channels
that actually have information and I can
we're doing all that like creating a
website stuff like that that's super
easy I like just a
it's just a placeholder and we're not
trying to keep it up to date in theory I
should be updating the wiki election
website I almost never do and it's
actually got some pages and stuff like
that but same issue so I volunteer for
that but just like right now it is a
website that someone had put three
months of time into to change from the
Wix website to the WordPress website I
don't want to hold it like that just
because it is that you already need it
some of the time and do it but I also
kind of do put up anyway
my I mean a landing page that is that
and maybe the other things because it at
least explains the sense-making
yeah where is it like is it hosted on
like the WordPress servers right now is
that the idea
I believe isn't WordPress just a a a
framework it do they actually do hosting
as well I feel like it's on Bluehost
well which is a WordPress but I might
also be wrong like this is where I'm not
techy and I can't even like get into my
wordpress account the easiest thing to
do is start with if we're only doing a
single page might just be a Google site
where it's like a single page throw it
online it's free
I think we can I think we can recover
so the together tech org and I think we
could get access to it your read the
name of the person that was helping you
out but I'm sure if I contact her again
she'd give me a login probably if he can
sit good yeah yeah my issue is like I
don't want to be the person that log
because I won't have to contact her
every time like the domain name or who
actually has like the other check or but
she's want to put this information up so
she's the one who actually knows how to
get an account but she sent me all the
information so like I can't afford that
oh yeah because if you actually have
like your you know an account with
GoDaddy or Google domains or whoever it
which comes to shove we don't actually
need our help because if we're not
keeping the existing site we can just
change where the site points to and then
we can do whatever we want
yeah yeah I mean but you know it's good
to check to see if we can reuse stuff
that exists the other tech is just the
YouTube channel at the moment right and
like how can we get people involved and
being part of
these conversations or other
conversations that are maybe more
interesting for them
look Jubilee you'll send that log and in
front of me and Andrea yeah I'll find
thee the email she sent me and figures
out of let me just write it out
WordPress login I have to go get a bait
card today so maybe not today
that's enough executive functioning for
me she'll pay my Red Sox won but I will
figure it out over the vibe next Friday
for sure like long before that and that
is idea cafe is changing its time
because Eric started a group that's
exactly during IDI cafe and he's
poaching some of the people and he wants
me in that group as well so I was like
okay we're making that at 9:30 and his
thing will be at 11:15 that day all
times in my time because at the standard
time but I'm excited I'm excited to have
a new YouTube channel that's like
dedicated to this and I think also being
able to communicate what it is we're up
to in the game be space like being able
to say like this isn't for our four
projects right this is for like the idea
is the one thing that got the most
attraction in the game be space so when
we put up project raising and how do we
facilitate helping people with their
projects while creating it at a project
while like something that actually works
and it's already giving value right and
I think project raising is that and
having conversations that people enjoy
being part of is is that but how to have
those conversations about project be on
a new YouTube channel that isn't just
the four of us right like also possibly
invention like mastermind groups having
a sense making project mastermind group
which is probably this one with - me
like you know they'd be like recent
score wiki election kind act like having
the ones that are kind of grouped
together around a common project which
is not what you're supposed to do with
mastermind groups but I think it is in
game be what you're supposed to do
absolutely and maybe they don't food
ones or whatever it is but having one
space for if they want to
your mastermind group and zoom and you
know you can upload it and say this is
if you're a game B mastermind group we
can you know post them all here and link
them in our playlist if they want to
post them on their own YouTube whatever
that is to have content that itself is
already the meta project and what that
looks like so um for me YouTube is
basically only the final point as a
outlet also but before that you so we
are going to use stream yard to do the
actual video calls or what are we going
to do for that stream assume something
where people can actually then come
together and then decide whether they
want to stream it live or just record it
or maybe yeah that's part of it the
Better Project yeah so the meta project
is the scheduler is like how would like
if people don't want to be live on
YouTube how do you get people into a
mastermind group right what does a
mastermind group look like that ended up
at selfish conversations to have either
on zoom or on YouTube but yeah to be on
YouTube stream yard works fairly well to
street live but not everyone's gonna
want to have it on everyone so like zoom
records fine and can be uploaded as well
but we don't have the technology to be
able to offer to people hey sign up and
we'll give you a mastermind group right
sign up and match you with the people
who also are into food that is kind of
partly what we're working through yeah
how do we do that to the best of our
ability with existing technology while
we're creating new technology and
getting people to be part of that
conversation so they have the energy to
want to create that and hopefully put
money into it right the four of us
creating a scheduler for cost $10,000
and each one of two thousand five
hundred others each right if there's a
hundred of us creating that because we
all have a project that we're interested
in in previous its and and more so
actually out of that hundred someone's a
amazing it right feel free to do it
yeah exactly and some of this I might be
able to build a knack the tool that I
used for the the wiki election
prototypes it's been pretty good I mean
it's not the prettiest thing but it
works in it lets you sort of do what
needs to get done what tool is that
again a true nak kan ack sort of like a
it's mostly it like a build your own
database you know where there's tables
and tables can we buy other tables and
then you can you know add records to
little stuff but there's some amount of
sort of automation and yeah yeah I'd
also suggest now I haven't played with
it yet but check out that bubble dot IO
cuz it's a similar tool if you hadn't
already checked it out yet but bubbler
bubble dot IO maybe ble we're talking
about record for you know in my life oh
yeah
so yeah that's a that's a way to make
complicated apps that's mostly drag you
drop you know code right okay and even
though I'm a software developer for 20
years I'd prefer to do that then write
everything from scratch at least when
you're experimenting so fair enough
I haven't played with it enough yet
though I'm just yeah I mean there's a
couple of those apps out there I saw a
few it sounds sort of like a nagger o.o
probably alternatives to each other so
be clear which one is can you still
access the code of bubble that I oh I
haven't looked at it yet
so I'm gonna have to see the reusability
and what happens when you hit their
walls I did look at dang it there's
another one out there web flow and web
flow looks pretty darn limited some
humpin bubble would be better so in a
button a couple weeks I should I should
have a good idea of what it takes to if
it's really do like a member portal with
it you cannot give you any logins and
people can poke vehicle yeah I mean
that's one of the things that it comes
built with the web flow doesn't is
interactivity like web flow has forms
but you can't do anything with it
bubble seems to have forms and interact
and workflows in the backend for some
automation and stuff but I haven't seen
what your what's your neck does I can't
do it sounds similar to bubble I'll
probably check that out and see how it
compares and no it sounds promising
anything that can help us kind of build
a basic scheduler as well as a certain
like Heather keeps sending me now
amazing projects that are possibly
savings we can use but there's too many
like I'm like I can't keep anything
straight I can't
and that's well to be able to do that to
be able to know what's going on
it gave me a not like what projects and
where they are
cuz a lot of them sound cool but they
don't exist yet and then some exist but
they're you know what I mean like
they're kind of selling you their vision
in the future when they're beta isn't
the greatest and then some of them are
amazing right now and it's like what
ones do we use and for any project right
not for necessarily for the four
together tech the meta project but like
which one does wiki like shabus if they
want to and you know figure out what
that process looks like as we figure out
what we would need in our figure well
that might be an interesting thing to
almost like create a catalog of all the
different apps that we sort of been
looking at save which ones we actually
use but also which ones we looked at and
decided like no not that one for these
reasons so no I saw the in the game B
group I saw the wiki that's almost
started where they have like all the
projects but I find that like just a
list like that is harder to work with
because I want to know like aspects
about it right like who's the person
involved and do they have a website
what's their social and sort of what
groups do they fit into and how much
money does it cost
exactly and like what if I said have you
been calling them it was mastermind
groups I've been calling them
coopertition councils okay sort of like
the groups were kind of a competition
but this is game B so not really
that's good yeah cuz you wind up on
multiple right like I know in the case
of flicky election it's kind of got the
reason score sense-making thing but
there's other parts too where if
somebody starts like a news aggregate
tool it would also kind of be that so
you might sort of end up being in these
different parts of things that you touch
to help talk about people who are also
doing that similar teacher or module
what sort of logic and stuff to to
consider there mm-hmm because the other
thing I would like to be able to do
which is not apps esses airily but we
talked about this as well I mean I think
you know my um for project raising like
not tomorrow's tomorrow's is
brainstorming about brainstorming part
two it should be awesome and that's more
about like anyone who doesn't have a
project how do they get involved in
things right but we don't have those
people necessarily quite yet like there
if we had hundreds of people who are
like poking out a project that would be
the one we'd saw but instead of you have
hundreds of people were like I have a
project give me people but so was that
point oh the next week after is James
Jones cube spawn and specifically we're
looking to find him funding like he has
a very specific aspiration which is that
he his project is expensive and he needs
to make a living right and his project
has a lot I think of potential for game
be like having an on-demand printing you
know what I mean like basically 3d
printing in your neighborhood is cool
and so even if we don't ever find him
funny and I want to be able to put on
the game B space if you're a funding
expert come participate in this but for
future having like expert panels right
that are like hey send it up to the
financial people that's who I mean
everyone's gonna want finance but also
like a metric of like are you ready for
financing he really is like he's been
getting it and doing that right like
you're like it'd be great if together
tech get financing what are we doing
with it we don't even bank account
doesn't deal with that right like to
know when you're capable of asking for
that expert panel as well as asking for
it like maybe you don't need that right
maybe it is just the four of us
brainstorming ways he could make money
as opposed to knowing how to get grant
knowing how to do crowdfunding and
knowing how to having angel investors
right like what is the but having a list
of people and their expertise is what I
was going for totally good who want to
be reached out for for that right
because if there's ten people or finance
and you like hey cube spawn that it's
gonna resonate with some people and not
with others and so those are the ones
who are gonna come and of course based
on their schedule so for that scheduler
um what kind of information do we only
to collect in what kind of parts are in
my mind um we definitely we need to have
that a scheduler like where where people
can agree on a certain time we need to
have different topics about what they
want to participate in a mastermind or
project racing or whatever and we need
to have the database of people with tags
of their individual expertise
potentially so whether someone is expert
in I wasn't necessarily saying they were
one tool but yeah that I mean that would
be awesome if it was a jeweler is just
getting people to conversations right
which could be a mastermind group that
meets every week in which case we need
them based on their topic and expertise
or their project one but it's like as a
individual I want a dashboard of all the
projects that I'm part of and I want my
schedule to make sense right so I want
to I know when I'm free and I want to
find people to talk to on that um it's
also very much about doing what we're
doing in a decentralized way so that
it's not broadcast right it's not we
have a board meeting of a million people
watch it it's a million people have a
conversation and how do we have anything
come out of that it's the like the
scheduler is how do you get people to a
conversation that and of itself is
powerful and then yes if we're if we
were creating the schedule for project
raising in general having a database of
your expertise is kind of
part of that but I think it would
naturally arise for the next iteration
of these people are having conversations
hey I had a conversation with someone
and they were a financial expert I'll
put you two in contact with each other
right which I guess the main point of of
all this is you have to get people
basically interested and get people to
participate what do we actually need to
get people to participate what makes
them come so I'm just brainstorming here
but for me one of the things is to see
what is available to see who they could
potentially connect with to have this
platform where they can put out promote
their own thing maybe or so these are
some things that if they can do that on
our schedule or platform then that is
already some incentive to come what else
would be out there that we could I'm
just trying to a yeah of this and of
course we can then iterate in what we
want to provide in the first place and
then I think that's really the question
of the meta project itself is what do
project like projects like ours it
earlier or later in the stage or the
same what would interest us what would
bring us on board start doing this stuff
that interests us first that will in
theory interest some other people who
are sort of like-minded they join on and
as that expands we start doing more and
born and figuring that stuff out so I
think it's just we just start doing it
for us we do it publicly and then adjust
on the fly as we need things and adds
people that join on need new things we
start figuring that that out and like
for the scheduler I'm sort of thinking
you know phase one isn't great right
it's just people can sort of even just
type out like I'm available on weekends
and this and that and here's my time
zone availability yeah and then you know
there's like maybe just a wall of here's
this person here's the times they're
available here's the stuff they're
interested in it's actually people going
through
sort of seeing the data be like oh I can
me at that time we have similar stuff
cool let's go up to the side and talk
about how we actually set it up say okay
I have that now created I don't need
that conversation anymore it'll be kind
of heavy and not very intuitive and sort
of more grunt work involved in trying to
figure out what whoo-hoo-hoo meets when
but then once we get to the point where
that's too cumbersome we've got a decent
sized community and we can start saying
hey what's our parity is it to fix the
scheduler great everybody caught up up
ten bucks and then or you know however
it ends up happening but then we can
actually start to build it out if the
scheduler is kind of working fine
because you know it's it's clunky but
you just set up your two or three groups
and then you don't need it anymore that
might last for a while if that made
sense yeah it kind of it because I was
expecting the scheduler that the beta
iteration to do a lot of that work to do
the connecting people but maybe not
maybe it is just your schedule and then
somebody else is like hey you both like
to talk about farming we've set you up a
farm in one rusty you know it's like
topic people like it needs to be time
and space that you can meet anatomic
yeah and if it can match you based on
that then okay I think we had like in
knack or bubble or wish it for at I we
have a list of all the people and then
we can do like you know what was
interested in what your talents are you
know when you when you as a person are
available and then a separate list of
the projects where like what categories
do they pull into who's currently
involved in that project what help do
they need and then you can start to add
on more be like okay well for the people
what are they interested in what do they
want to meet on and then start to find
where people have similar interests and
availabilities and then okay you three
overlap you have this you know you're
all working on sense-making and you've
all said that you're available you know
around the same time on Sunday is cool
we can start to meet up we log that
we're no longer looking for sense-making
groups because we found one and we're no
longer available at that time
on Sundays and then that's you know I
think fairly hard to use to start with
because it's just the like tracking the
people in the projects and that it won't
be super easy to use but the goal is
that once it starts to become a problem
we can start as a community to say when
do we need to fix this
when is this becoming too hard to use
too hard to maintain when do we need to
actually you know start to work together
to actually build something that isn't
just popsicle sticks and glue yeah and
showcasing that it's popsicle stick
singl ooh there's someone behind the
scenes figuring this out and that is the
piece that's not working because it's
like X amount of hours and paying them
for it possibly so are at least
assigning a currency value to it so like
hey look we've spending five hundred
dollars a week doing this we can be
spending five hundred dollars a year
creating that technology I keep it in
place but for me like although the
projects is what is bringing people in
like the project raising and together
tech of like what can we create that's
gonna facilitate your project
the scheduler itself kinda has to be
designed for the individual working on
the project as opposed to the project
but both like an individual if I want to
help wiki elections I want to know when
they're speaking and I want to become
and watch or be part of those
conversations more so I want to be able
to know which conversations I'm a part
of them what's happening
this might actively becomes the really
early version of the talent exchange
that we were talking about and it has to
be both you have to be able to see as a
project here's what I I need help with
and as as talent you can go to that
exchange and say here's all the projects
that need you know like I I guess STL I
would say here's what my talents are
they can say here's all the projects
that need that kind of help go search
through them and see what you like yeah
and then schedule a news conference at
with that person but I I'm also talking
more people without a project or a
talent who are just like yes I'm gonna
come and raise somebody's project right
I'm gonna come in brainstorm I'm gonna
come
and work what can I do with wiki lection
because there's this big and maybe we're
not solving that problem yet even though
it's the problem I really want to solve
is people don't know where they fit and
they don't know that they even are
valuable and so being able to give them
the opportunity to be part of a
conversation like the Omega roll
conversation which is what Eric the one
on Tuesday is becoming it's the ideas
it's gonna grow as big as it wants to
grow up to 100 people and we're gonna
break them off into zoom conversations
so that's one of the reasons he invited
me as he knows that's what I'm focusing
on it's like how do we have a conference
how do we do that conversation and like
oh yeah okay
so just make a rule I think then what
we're sort of talking about is we're
gonna have almost like a pipeline for
projects or like you know flow you start
off here you go through here you go
through these stages and a part of the
meta project is creating sort of a
framework for what that looks like as
you move through it how's that we're
also talking about sort of like a talent
building pipeline or telling
identification pipeline where you start
off saying okay everybody has this
talent of just being a human being with
opinions and beliefs everyone has that
everyone takes that box everyone starts
there anybody can take part in a project
raising because you're just saying as a
human being here's what I think and
there are certain talents and then part
of the framework for how the projects or
the meta project is arranged is if let's
say you've got like a funding
conversation where you have a couple
people who have raised your hands and
say I'm an expert in this I've done work
in this great you have them you have the
person who sort of actually needs the
funding but but then you've got like I
don't know your your your acolytes your
people who said I'm interested in this
I'm not good enough to leave the
conversation yet but I want to see if a
it's interesting and B if I have some
good opinions if I can chime in here and
there where those sessions aren't just
meant for expert talking to project
leader it's also meant to sort of
identify and build that skillset
indicate in the community so those those
meetings become at least three different
types like three types of people your
expert your project person and then
people who are learning and trying to
sort of get get a grasp on that space
and that becomes their pipeline of used
here you start at the spot everyone has
that talent and then we build a
framework for you know how you can
explore and start to identify where your
strengths are and what you enjoy I mean
yes and it's all like it's as an
individual I'm coming in without needing
to get anywhere go anywhere know my
strengths or talents it's it's the
barrier of getting on social media right
I'm not on Twitter to figure out my per
but also yeah we can figure out your
purpose and help guide you towards that
if that's meaningful to you if you want
to be part of these conversations we're
starting from a place of meta project
because that's the one that got game you
know like people have projects they
don't want to let their project go and a
company part of something meta and nor
should they have to but we're not
necessarily designing a pipeline that
like you get to keep your project and
create you know like its how do we
create a scheduling tool so whatever
your idea is you can have conversations
around it right you can from the like
spark of an idea to you know what if
there were dozens of people having
little mastermind groups about wiki
election right you mean that you're not
even a part of right just like hey what
would we want in AI in a you know like
how to decentralize decision-making
right how to obey sound ever really yes
my plan is sort of how to get there
because you need to have a library of
people first and your point of it's hard
to sort like people don't always know
where they fit and people don't know
what they don't know yeah it's sort of
well as a part of the meta project one
of the main things that we talked about
is giving you know these types of
projects a framework of okay here's sort
of why you should join but you can just
see that by watching us talk about our
projects watching the framework unfold
and saying this not a project what does
it look like what sort of you know like
the project raising what are the the
stages what sort of things can it offer
that it sounds like we're already
heading in the direction of providing
that use to project owners I don't have
to talk about what that looks like and
how you know the any sort of like
alliance of people with with similar
book police but for the talent portion
giving them something similar where you
know even as a project owner if
you want like if you're really good at
marketing or really good at programming
you're like well I like my project but I
can also work on other projects as well
because you know I'm only especially if
in exchange I can I can find somebody
who's you know if I'm a coder and
somebody else is awesome at marketing if
we can trade services for our projects
then we're taking use of like oh well I
could spend 10 times the amount of time
to do this or you can do it in one tenth
the time and I can do that one time I
view let's use our time wisely but then
to actually start to build that pipeline
of people who can do that work right and
start to say hey even if you aren't sure
where you fit in everyone fits in here
start here join these sessions do this
and then at the same time that we're
building our framework for what projects
could go through to get where they want
to be we have a separate pipeline for
people to provide you know some talent
to two projects where the goal is if you
already know your talent grit tell us
what it is and you can get plugged in
and figure out what you know where you
want to spend your time if you don't if
you you don't know that you wanted to
take part but you aren't sure where you
fit start here and have a framework for
identifying talent and identifying your
interests and you know structured in a
way we're at the end of it you can say
all right you can help with these
projects they need your help do you like
any of these or at the very least here
are the talents that you've indicated
and I mean it's cataloging people and
cataloging ideas he catalog any
facilitating that back-end so that if
you have an idea you can find people who
have who want to work on that with you
or if you have a talent to find where
that most best fits and if you don't
have like everyone has a talent and it's
being you yeah exactly
well and as far as like counts that
could move a project forward not
everyone has the same talents but
everyone is gonna have at least one like
you're gonna have something that like is
you know is is interesting to you and
you can do well well I mean I'll I think
that there are certain core talents that
every project needs and whether or not
you're good at that if you're willing to
take that on especially for a very baby
project
you're growing and that it's growing
right like if somebody wanted to come
take marketing on put together tech I
don't need them to have a degree or them
to want to do it like here it's like yes
someone cool awesome like you're gonna
do better than we're currently doing
because we're not really doing much
right but once you get to a certain
level then you want a marketing team and
then there's you know people people on
it it's helping people where they are to
get to where they want to be which is I
think people do want to help and they
don't feel capacity to be able to do
that and if it's super simple for them
to be able to do it just being part of a
conversation have any conversation and
figuring out what your talents are
having you know you want to take
accounting you know like this is
actually a need that a lot of people
have and your mind seems to be something
that can take that on do you want to
quit within it but I think it's also
something that naturally arises from the
scheduler like something that once you
have people with projects hey I need
marketing who knows marketing right and
then like okay we've all talked to Jim
Jim's the expert of marketing let's get
that down in like a more concrete way so
that it's easier to find Jim and Jim's
yeah but I think as soon as we start
working on like talent and their needs
that's going beyond the need of what I
picture when I hear the word scheduler
I just think here's times I'm available
here's time you're available we want to
meet up - a time that works there's that
layer on top that I think is what we're
talking about where it's like okay that
project has identified that they need
these three these three talents who has
okay and that's sort of how it picks who
needs to be involved and that's where it
can be sort of complex and say hey
there's three people who could be
involved her marketing let's look at all
of their availability Oh only one
matches all right well then we we found
their match yeah if you need to meet at
the same time and that's where the
scheduler maybe doesn't like for a
project wait for a wiki elections you
need to meet at the same time to meet
for together tech we probably want to
figure out how to have people not have
to be made at 11 o'clock on Friday right
be involved in it because we want their
expertise we want you know I mean we
want to know what would work for your
project so that they're wanting to help
with an or us but the scheduler itself I
think we maybe want to pick three types
of a conversation right a mastermind
group a project raising a Omega rule
group right and design it to do to just
the scheduling right for those three
things and then people would want to
sign up to say hey I'm I want a
mastermind group right we don't need to
do anything else like I want to find
other people in the game be space to
practice the Omega roll with and so then
you have and then when people here we
have this and they have a project
they're gonna bring people on board but
they're also an anyone this brought on
board is brought on board for everyone
right which is what a lot of the stuff
out there doesn't do like you can pay
for media sorry you can pay for tech
that helps you coordinate a team but
then you're paying per team member but
the team member doesn't have a dashboard
where they can be involved in many
different projects and it's that's what
we like people are bringing people right
they're already bringing their
connections they're already bringing
that worth and as long as there's
something there for them and that's
where I think there's something there
for them being more individual and less
project where anyone who doesn't have a
project those are the people we actually
want cuz they're the ones who are going
to be giving their ideas in time freely
and willingly to everything but we also
want the projects because that seems to
be in game V space or a lot of energy is
right and that's where you actually
apply the work as it were right so if
you're coming with talent there's
nowhere to apply that talent why are we
doing all right I also feel this has
been like for the least of us 50 minutes
of Brisco conversation greatly John
history what are your thoughts I was
just typing up some stuff in the agenda
some ideas and some of the things that
you've been talking about I'm not sure
what I caught them well I was also
wondering like so we all I think assume
okay we have video conversations do we
also want to have a chat and things like
that
I think I think something like that
would be probably also quite important
and then to each of the conversations
having the ability to catch something at
a document or some some posts to keep
summaries and maybe before that
questions or so that we're talking about
the next one or whatever so that people
can see a little bit in text form what
is this about um just giving some
context I think a lot of it is just the
projects doing it what like it right so
you for your project if you start to get
people interested your number one goal
is just to move your project forward so
as soon as you get the person interested
if they want to chat if they want to do
a phone call if they want to send
postcards whatever you agree is the way
that you want to communicate you try it
out I think sort of the next step there
is we make some sort of a mastermind
group or a cooperation counselor however
its structured and so let's say the
Bentley Jonas and I meet as sort of the
the sense-making group and Eunice talks
about what he's been doing what's
working for his projects and dentally
talks about oh I just tried this for
reason score and it worked great or it
didn't work so well and we start to see
what works in and what doesn't
then when we're working on the meta
project we take those exact learnings
and say okay well two of us tried this
and it worked this seems like something
that maybe we can recommend other
projects do and maybe you know Jonas and
I tried something and I really didn't
work so we say all right we tried this
didn't work great will advise against
this and we start to actually get some
data points as we're trying things up
for our projects and then trying to
apply those learnings to building the
meta project does that make sense yeah I
think it does make sense I'm wondering
whether yeah so those learnings that we
applied them to okay how are we going to
get more people involved and interested
in other future our projects is that
what you mean
partially yeah so there's a lot of it
right there's trying to generate
interest and that's one thing that we
all want to do for our project so
there's different strategies there and
things of hey we all tried this to get
people interested on our own there's
also the meta project will have its own
way to try to get people interested that
we can't really replicate anywhere cuz
there's only one that a project but the
things that we're trying individually in
projects that's sort of our petri dishes
right so we can each have our own thing
and then as we're trying to eat these
things that hey I tried this on my
project either at work or it didn't
here's one data point and then if we
each do it we'll have a bunch of
different data points that we can start
to see what works and what doesn't that
gives us one sort of frame of reference
for if you have a project like ours
here's things that we've tried and we're
trying to build a framework so if we get
ten projects that are kind of similar
involved and they all try this thing and
it works for nine of them that's pretty
good okay we might recommend that and
and that can be including trying to get
people on board but they can also be
trying to coordinate with people trying
to build things
anything from start to finish of your
project in the end the meta project kind
of needs to help with all of it
yeah so I think at the beginning what
you're honest is like having if we're
have if we're facilitating a video
conversation and that's what the
schedulers doing one of the first things
needs to be right and how do we keep in
contact outside of this right how do we
like and that will be a conversation
each bird needs to have and they are
beyond what's up are we on Facebook are
be on and missing but honestly a space
that's like the URL it's the Google Doc
or we're on Facebook writing it like
we've decided this is the best bet for
this group and constantly Burnie coming
into it with this is well I'm not on
Facebook right I'm not I'm not on it
what's up it's like right but this group
is so you're kind of and eventually we
get to the meta problem of we need our
own exactly end up being something that
for each project if we're tracking it
that might be one of the things that
we're tracking is like here's how this
group is communicating if you don't want
to
communicate on that channel don't join
that group and then in the end the goal
had a platform that we're all on the
same thing and that sort of takes out
that friction yeah yeah I do kind of see
the scheduler as a separate I mean these
things may be tied together but I kind
of see it as separate from the kind of
like database of projects and then my
preference would be not to have any sort
of chat functionality or comment
functionality on the database of
projects keep that very lean and they
could just link out to where their
community is and so we need to keep the
data set within the or my suggestion is
to keep the data within the kind of
project listing as minimal as possible
now that's Jonas is probably getting at
how to make it attractive which of
course that's not very attractive but I
also don't want to make another place
that these project managers have to
monitor and maintain right - to be clear
I'm not saying that we actually do the
communication in the tool I'm saying
that we specify like set in stone - just
say anyway you know so for this project
if he says he wants to use whatsapp
great in the project it says this
project uses whatsapp that's how we
communicate if you're gonna join that
project you better off watch that
because otherwise I don't know I don't
think that was John this is suggestion
but yes I was more replying to Jonah's
suggestion than yours yeah that makes
sense yeah I I was yeah yeah yeah you're
completely right I was thinking in terms
of you know if we have all the tools to
facilitate communication and track
keeping and some external that well
we'll make it all complicated slower
unattractive whatever and so I was
thinking in my head I okay good we have
this thing where we have everything
internal and practical and stuff but
definitely one thing is it creates
additional overhead for moderating and
forever and also we would need to create
it which is
lot of work so um it may be seeing a
Fiat Li we we definitely have to keep
everything more less everything external
um and then after some while we can
reassess that if we want to bring some
often maybe most useful things so yeah I
think we could we could start that right
now like the database of projects just
open up a Google spreadsheet to be an
open edit and then add your own me and
Jonas put in our projects and and jublee
or I could put in together tech as its
own project and put those links like
where do you communicate just you know
we can start figuring out what the
columns are as we need them that's one
way to kind of start yeah I think
finally starts at Google's especially my
end goal was to put that in a core
bubble or wherever so that we can have
like a little project so with the people
and then the projects that will end up
getting fairly unwieldy and we can
decide what to show and want to hide and
do and who sees what so one of the
things that's a little less techie
that's that for what you guys are
talking the ly said like three different
types of projects that the scheduler can
do and I think instead of you know make
a rule faster mind would love having it
be one-off conversations right like ones
where it's like I want to have one
conversation about Star Trek and game B
and here's a schedule set right and if
there's different people available at
different times it makes one-off
conversations forever anyone as well as
forming a group writes you're gonna meet
with the same people weekly that's your
mastermind group that's let's talk to
Star Trek every week let's have a Star
Trek you know conversation and then also
conferences so that maybe you have a big
problem you want to solve what does that
look like that one's gonna be much more
difficult but it's just getting a number
of people to a bigger chunk of time
right or repeated ties and then breaking
them off into groups and that in and of
itself both brings people at the
conference it's gonna bring new people
one-off conversations brings new people
and then you're gonna keep coming back
for the group right to build that
actually
it's like micro Sol linearity groups
facilitated by the macro scheduler that
is as beta as possible in the beginning
maybe we only do one of those things
maybe it's just one-off conversations
once you've scheduled a one-off
conversation you just keep coming back
weekly if you want to you know like
something that's yeah simpler I think
the scheduler the the niche that is not
fulfilled by current tech is mostly that
piece of getting together with four
random people out of a larger group of
people because if you do have a
recurrent group then you could use
something like doodle and if you have a
conference then really it's the
conference organizers or schedule that
kind of sets it so I think we can expand
it those but I think the beginning is
you know we have 50 people and game B if
I wanted to have a conversation with
random four people it's a pain right now
to do that mm-hmm but how is how is what
we are creating really helping in that I
mean Jubilee already you know posts in
in Facebook about some of those
conversations is it like the fact that
these conversations are set in time and
with our scheduler they are flexible and
we can come with some other people to a
different time agreement that would like
help a lot or yeah I think it's mostly
right now there Julie's initiative and
so she's saying up the times and a lot
of people can't make those times and
it's it's a bit of a pain on her it's
it's a lot of work for her and it would
be a lot of work for anyone else trying
to do it and I can only schedule one
conversation right there just the ones
I'm part of the idea is if we're trying
to arrange conversations for specific
topics is the key thing that we're truck
like if they do pick one of these two to
fix first is it trying to find a time
that works for everyone or is it trying
to identify like these topics that
people want to meet on and who wants to
meet on them and how many are there
the scheduler part
about the topic because the taught like
the idea is were individuals who can
come up with a topic and then I want to
bring people together to talk about that
topic so we can generate topics all day
long it's not really we don't want like
a set number of topics and then we might
want a set number for efficiency and for
bringing people together like we're
talking about these three ones so we're
not dissipating the energy but mainly if
you can get people together to talk
about something um they're gonna like
it's finding those people and fighting
the time they're available and then
being able to reproduces so it's not
everyone watching our idea Cafe is
people getting to participate in idea
cafe right getting to actually have
those conversations and on on topics
that are of interest to them and and to
be clear I think we have kind of
combined these two concepts there is the
like building together tech and building
this when really the core niche for the
scheduler is really kind of like
building a community and our our focus
of it right now is game B but could be
other communities and having broader
kind of nebulous discussions between a
large group of people by having a meta
rate on topics and stuff so I don't know
jublia correct me if I'm wrong if those
are actually kind of like two different
goals I mean one kind of feeds into the
other but you know I'm saying so I don't
know that the scheduler is actually
directly related to us getting more
people to work on projects now that I'm
thinking about it in my mind it sounds
like the scheduler something will end up
needing once we not even hit scale but
like yet you know let's say 50 people
involved there's gonna be a certain
point where like all right we have them
involved they want to work on it you
know a drill or Jubilee or Bentley or or
whoever is doing the actual scheduling
is like you know what with spending
eight hours a week on this this is
ridiculous we have to automate this
mmm-hmm I can sort of you do it manually
until it's painful and then you say okay
we need to start to work on this it can
be issue is it's already painful because
of time zones right like if we all have
the same time zone then it'd be like
who's available with it so when I'm
it's like what time is that your time
how do we find a time that works for all
of us it doesn't exist out there yet and
having something like that where it's
just like sorry say that saying to get a
group of people their time zones and
what times work for everyone but
everyone for flavor but really how many
people did you have that were interested
in in your conversations that couldn't
come because of time zone I mean right
now for example I'm wondering whether
these are really many people mm-hmm like
I'm in your sealant I'm I'm actually for
me it's Saturday morning and sometimes
the project racing is at 6:00 a.m. in
the morning for me but I'm interested
and I'm coming but how many people do
they say are now at this time doesn't
work and that's why I'm not coming I'm
definitely restricted that way you've
been in many of our cults already on
weekends but I'm actually here on my
lunch break right now so I was able to
like arrange it there and arranged
around it but if it was like an hour
earlier later I probably couldn't well I
really don't know how many more people
would be able to attend one of these if
we had the scheduler that's poor I think
that's a valid question yeah and if you
were in let's say like India would the
time zones overlap it's the wrong way to
not let you attend because you know it
would be 11 p.m. or 1 a.m. er well yeah
whatever time okay yeah I'm a little bit
like yeah with I'm having similar
concerns as Bentley in any way that I'm
also a drill that I'm wondering whether
what we are discussing about will really
make it more attractive to people to
come and this initial step of getting to
a 50 people participation or so
at that time then I can definitely see
our a scheduler would be really great
but before that I'm wondering whether
there might be something that it's much
more useful yeah yeah I know almost like
we need I think we need an in-between
step from where we are now where it's
this sort of nebulous thing of people
can post stuff on Facebook and Facebook
isn't great for this anyway because
you're never sure which posts you're
seeing and you know you're at the mercy
of their algorithm as opposed to putting
it somewhere else like you know a Google
sheet or knack or bubble and so you can
have a list of here's all of the
meetings that people want to touch a
host and if they're for a purpose like
so if jubilee says oh I want to hold
something you know on Sundays at 2:00
p.m. my time cool here's a time people
can sign up for it start with just a
really simple approach that sort of we
have more control over and then our our
first goal is to make that a problem is
to get so many people involved and
interested in raising their hand and
saying I want to participate in these
times or I want to participate but you
don't have a time that works for me just
start that to start just building to
deal with the people where our whole
goal is to make these scheduler become a
necessity yeah and I think that and
happy not in a way that I think that's
great like we're having this
conversation on YouTube so that that's a
barrier to some people right they don't
want to be live they don't want to be
but like when you write we're willing to
move on to zoom right you're like that's
not where there's enough people we want
more people than we want you know to be
necessarily to be here there's tons of
conversations to happen on zoom but
people need to know they're happening
and then show up to them to the leader
if it's live or not like comfortable
being live cool yours will probably be
yellow but having a calendar for all of
the conversations that people are
willing to be part of as well as the
barrier right here on the street yard
six is the maximum and quite frankly
because this is our fix our world Friday
we probably don't want people to showing
up and being part of it because it's not
good at they're not going to know what's
going on but watch three and then you're
welcome to come right
like watch and then you can be part of
it but the the mastermind right unit
like a set group of people the idea cafe
I care more like what just needs to stop
at six people right but I don't know
like we have the one on Star Wars on
Tuesday and people didn't show up it was
just Brent and I because I didn't post
it cuz I thought it was gonna be popular
and so I didn't want too many people
showing out so actually having like
there's this many spots who's filling
them up and then also don't fill them up
if you're not going to be there right
later
like you know that you're gonna be there
you're not there why weren't you there
figure that out for your own calendar
it's like yeah I think it's to build it
specifically for like I want to meet on
this add it to something that we're not
at the mercy Facebook here's our max
here's who signed up maybe a waiting
list so like here's the six that have
said yep I'll be there here's the next
six where if somebody doesn't join up
here's the order if you're around you
can still attend and then we make do it
that until it you know hopefully until a
little bit before becomes super painful
so that we have time to actually work on
it and thing and then we have our team
of people to ask them hey how does this
work for you we're thinking about
building it that way I think it also for
idea cafe in particular works very well
for like oh I can't make that time like
it can literally just like I would come
but I can't make that time right I would
like one and a different time in we just
know that there's 80% of people can't
make it or there 5% of people who can't
make it right and oh we filled up our
six there's another six here in the
waitlist guess what there's two
conversations you can both have them
like it's and so I think if we can maybe
that's next week's agenda is talking
about creating that that beta like
that's it
spreadsheet okay right and creating it
and game be for like conversations for
ones that like I know Eric starting the
one on Tuesdays and it's going to be I
believe as many people as want to come
and participate in Omega conversation
but it's like 11:15 and then breakout
groups right which is cool I think
that's what Eric's vision is you could
have that every day of the week in the
in the you know like creating those type
of things to say facilitate the game be
conversation and
people with projects who are going to
want to have more meta conversations
about how to be create projects all
right bra or over the hour should we say
goodbye to YouTube anyone will have any
closing statements they would like to
you're muted badly you're muted yes we
should finish no I don't have a closing
statements all right